Union Congregational Church (Lenox and Sullivan, N.Y.) Records
Union Congregational Church (Lenox and Sullivan, N.Y.) Records
1814-2005
1814-1945
Union Congregational Church (Lenox and Sullivan, N.Y.)
0.5 linear ft.
Minutes, treasurer records, and membership records of a church in Madison County; modern transcripts and National Historic Places registry documentation
149292
Biographical History
The Union Congregational Church in Lenox and Sullivan is an American Congregational Church founded in 1814 in Madison County, New York. It was reincorporated as the Oneida Lake Congregational Church in 1847. Construction of the building, which is one of the oldest standing churches in Madison County, began in 1824; it has been added to and expanded over the years and was listed on the National Registers of Historic Places in 2005.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Union Congregational Church (Lenox and Sullivan, N.Y.) Records contains meeting minutes, treasurer's records, and membership records, as well as documentation regarding the church's inclusion on the National Register of Historic Places. Some of the volumes have been transcribed.
Subject and Genre Headings
New York State; Church and clergy; Oneida Lake Congregational Church.; Union Congregational Church (Lenox and Sullivan, N.Y.); Church buildings -- New York (State); Church records and registers -- New York (State) -- Lenox.; Church records and registers -- New York (State) -- Sullivan.; Congregational churches -- New York (State) -- Lenox.; Congregational churches -- New York (State) -- Sullivan.; Congregationalists -- New York (State) -- Lenox.; Congregationalists -- New York (State) -- Sullivan.; Madison County (N.Y.); Oneida Lake (N.Y.); Church registers.; Financial records.; Minutes (administrative records)
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Volume of minutes and historical records, gift of A. P. Corman, 1969.
Five volumes plus transcripts, gift of Sandy Wilsey, 2020.
Inventory
- Administrative records
  - Church trustee records, 1845-1909 (Box 1)
    Gift of Sandy Wilsey, 2020
  - Incorporation documents, 1814; 1824,; 1847; photocopies (Box 1)
  - Minutes and membership records, 1814-1837 (Box 1)
    Gift of A. P. Corman, 1969
  - Minutes and membership records, transcript, 1814-1837; typed transcript of above volume (Box 1)
  - Oneida Lake Society Records, 1847-1945 (Box 1)
- Financial records
  - Treasurer's books, 1910-1914 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's books, 1921-1984 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1965-1967; 1971 (Box 1)
- Historic registry documentation
  - National Register of Historic Places application, 2005 (Box 1)